Now when I reach there come see say
two court we just fight finish. So then
say make them just settle then say make
them just invite me to come MC the
settlement say we all these black we
take MC their program say change some
things for my body later somebody come
meet me again say I make them they laugh
like small children.
So they make them they feel like say
they never put hand for bad thing
before.
[cheering]
for takot
now. Good evening.
I just they return from my auntie
barrier.
When I go the burial the things then why
I see there just make me realize say
no be every food then suppose they share
for burial
get some food then where they not
supposed they share for burial at all
but we make
we make the person where die they feel
like say then then they happy saying die
maybe every food then any food where
make person do like maybe I need for
burial no good no good no good at all
person
make the person die think just person
no they do all those things it's not
it's not nice
person dance for my auntie burial so
they she sustain injury for her leg how
you go which kind joy They your heart
when you go dance for person burial till
you wound what you want tell people now
say you take get that wound
I mean they dance for person burial now
I come wound which kind of lifestyle be
that way you just understand some people
on I notice on I notice the way things
they cost now
it don't you know say before they
complain about this thing now it don't
go another level people they cook now
ingredients not they complete for the
food
I go my friend house me and him eat a
bar till we chop finish I don't know say
now vegetable soup we chop
now when we don't chop finish
I come tell this your soup sweet
say what make no say nobody cook
vegetable soup
I said why you they brag? I know they
talk about vegetable soup. I they talk
of this one we we chop.
He said same thing we talk man. I said
no be the same thing we talk.
He said when I chop I said it not taste
like vegetable. I said it taste like
vegetable. He said say now vegetable be
that say me they go find leaf inside.
Say leaf not supposed inside every
vegetable.
Because of because of the price because
of the price of all these things any
show way then call me now I they go I
they go if you they celebrate anything
now call me now they go if you like make
them want behead somebody and call me I
go go I go MCM so ladies and gentlemen
we're here for the beheading of Mr.
Jonathan
who has been very stubborn and has ended
his life in this tragic way. I go MC
then call me recently to Bini say MC one
gathering
and the mistake where I do I don't ask
them say who they gather
now when I reach there I come they see
say now two cult we just fight finish so
then say make them just settle now then
say make them just invite me to come MC
the settlement party no be small thing I
reach there been wear black suit wear
black shoe. When I reach there and I
want start to the MCM, somebody come
meet me say
whether they not tell me say n settle
then they settle today. I said I said
don't tell me he said then what make
only the other people color come
say wear all this black why we take MC
their program say they go change some
things for my body so I come the sho the
shoe somebody come bring white canvas
come give me I come wear they come give
me white anchor shift m do pocket filler
so two white come my body I come begin
they talk they talk some people come
they laugh they laugh later somebody
come meet me say
I I won't cause problem for this place
say I think they tell me say now settle
then they settle say we didn't ignore my
joke now only the other court they
relate to the jokes
relate to that say make I talk something
we go sweet everybody
come begin they talk talk all of them
come they laugh laugh later somebody
come meet me again
I they make them they laugh like small
children.
So they make them they feel like say
they never put hand for bad thing
before.
They make I talk joke make them feel
like bad guys.
Suffer way they suffer.
No, but are they are they used are they
used to all these things because of my
upbringing and where we where I come
from? They don't already train me for
life. be kind lessons where we learn.
You get how I know some people they call
humble background.
We been poor no be humble background.
Nothing humble inside that thing. That
thing no humble at all. That no humb
because I I know my father plan but
money no day. So nothing humble inside
that thing. Nothing humble inside. So we
we been poor. It get our poverty even
rich. Get one time the poverty come
begin they protect us.
Yes, our poverty begin protect us for
the whole of our compound only our house
not enter
say no enter but if you enter to come
outside they had well because the house
tight well well because now very small
house now one room and we plenty where
my father born plus other relatives wake
they stay with us cuz my father get big
heart but you know get big house to take
attach the big heart so so
now that one room now we just they share
E they stay. No honestly if you h that
room it t even we where they stay the
house we they use caution because he get
person where they go out first before
every other person go to go out. If that
person if wrong person go outside they
ah nobody come out that day now people
go come help us. So now so the house we
treat the house like cult
say for cult if you enter come outside
again. So now so we finish anything we
want to outside before we enter the
house. Now so the house a very strange
house like that. So thieves know they
enter get one time one of our neighbor
come borrow knife from us. would even
they tell say no enter no enter no green
just enter
collect the knife now to come out begin
they struggle they struggle they
struggle they push they struggle they
shout when they shout in recognize
person where they in corner say no be
you they show your picture for TV say
you don't lost the guy say no be small I
come discuss business with their father
since last week now they try to come out
no
ah again one time one thief come he just
open our cutting he Just see people back
just facing all of them they sweat face
and the guy shocking shout say Jesus.
He said what all of they do inside here.
We say our house on house now stand like
this. We say yes. He said I know they
sleep. We say we sleep. He say how they
take sleep. We say sleep. We sleep like
this.
We know they lie down sleep for sleep.
We sleep. You just go the dist
face me after like 2 minutes nobody
don't turn
we go turn person we different need to
turn first then others turn small don't
no worry we go turn just wait patience
patience
the guy say we on our father we go sh
make you see him but they just know they
are with us just know then he get one
time where one unlucky thief cuz now new
thief he just come the area you know ask
question he just come just jump enter
inside the house thief finish to come
out now come hang
their struggle struggle struggle
struggle so they reach one time begin
they threaten us all
leave me I want
I DON'T
I GO I GO shoot I go shoot now my
younger sister brother you go raise your
hand try
begin say person
begin shoot I kill
see person even breathe against I
breathe I know make
fine. Make call police. CALL POLICE.
MAKE CALL POLICE. DON'T ENTER the house.
Make call police.
[cheering]
Daddy [cheering]
waiting. I want to talk to my father.
Daddy, I've been looking for a way to
see you since. But it's not like I don't
want to see you. It's just that the the
protocol,
you know, like no, it's not like it's
not like they're not doing a good job.
But I don't know one particular guy, you
always park me very far from the church.
You before I walk from that side to the
church or it's already fifth service
most times. there's no way to see you.
So because of that now me too I've I've
decided to join the protocol team in
Leky church
so that people will not suffer what I'm
suffering.
So me I I try my best to park people
close to the church like if you come
late now the church is in Leki I used to
tell them to park somewhere very close
to the church at lei that you know you
know you know Lagos now daddy so you
know that that place is very close to
it's not even far it's just like from
here to a greater it's not [cheering]
it's not that far like that so that's
why I just tell people to stay yes So
ah
you see the the things that has been
happening I will come and come and share
it with you.
Honestly, I just I just don't understand
this life. Whenever good thing happens
to you, people will just come out to
take credit.
And like that time they they gave me
that appointment. Daddy
this life. If you see if you see people
that came to me to tell me they were the
ones that made it happen.
I don't know where they came. Cameraman
in government house. I just got there.
He started telling me and governor since
morning money no be small fight because
of you
just understand some people
and see daddy I know those those people
that used to back me far from the church
I know it's not really their fault
because ever since I it's been long
since we saw so that our resemblance is
now reducing.
It's now it's now reducing. So they
don't used to know that I'm your son any
anymore. So So I I said I will look for
a way to to renew it. Yeah. Because
because in my family we normally look
like whatever is taking care of us.
So
we if you come to my family now, you
won't know who we look like cuz anytime
my father has money, we look like him.
So anytime my mother has money, we look
like her too. And so the thing used to
hurt my father. So sometimes he used to
go and borrow money just to make sure we
look like him. So So what we do is the
thing is not it's it's a it's like it's
something that is just there. It's not
like we do it on our own. And if the
money is not coming from you direct,
then we don't look like you. And so
whenever our father goes to borrow money
from our landlord, we start looking like
our landlord.
Yes. So that's that's what we do. So
like now now daddy like now that time I
was telling you about that 10 million
thing that time now and if you give me
that money now me and you carbon copy no
if you see nobody nobody will see the
difference.
I will even come here and preach on your
behalf they won't notice. Nobody will
know.
>> [cheering]
>> That's what
Yes. So, so the the the only the only
person we we don't like to look like in
our house is my grandmother because she
has a gift of complaining.
My grandmother can My grandmother
complains for everything. When the rain
touch her, she complained. So that the
rain is too hard on her. That doesn't
the rain know she's a she's an old
woman. Why is he hitting her like that?
My grandmother complained in the church
when they gave her holy communion.
She said the bread is not today bread.
What what what even annoyed me is the
fact that she was looking for today
bread as if it's today that Jesus died.
I just I just don't understand.
So
that this period I've been studying my
Bible so much. So I've come to realize
that there is one thing that God hates
so much and that is gossip.
And God does not like we believers to
always gossip. He does not like it at
all. That is why you see that wherever
two or three are gathered, he's always
there to make sure they are praying and
not gossiping. He's always there to make
sure things are okay. [cheering] Yes.
No. No. We used to stress God too much
because most times you just see people
gather Christians you think they are
praying they just gossiping if you see
pastor shoot today things that does not
concern you just be so used to stress
god like god will be here now thinking
they are praying another people gather
there he will go again he's always there
when two or three are gathered that's
why during that lockdown ah god was very
happy
because that time there was no way for
two or three to gather because of social
distancing so god was resting a lot.
That [cheering]
[applause]
that is not a small thing. Oh, during
that lockdown period, a lot happened
though. People started stealing up and
down. If you see my area, people were
just stealing things up and down.
Stealing. Some people came late for
because that time they were looting.
Some people they arrived there late. So
there was nothing to steal. So So one of
them stole signboard.
and and left with it just like that.
People were just taking different things
at that time. If you see people were
just attacking me every day, taking
things from me because that time I left
Lagos and I went to Bayasa. I discovered
that every house in Baya had one one
thief.
I didn't even because because of the the
way people were robbing now. So
everybody was protecting themselves. If
you come to this family and steal now,
they'll get upset and send their own
thief out. to man to go and thief too.
So it was it was just like that. People
were just stealing stealing things up
and down. It was was it was very nice.
So he it got and it got to a to a point
they they started stealing uh too much.
So I don't know how how it happened.
They I started owing them cuz they were
stealing from they were stealing from me
a lot. So it got to a point they search
me and they don't see anything. They
tell me you so
[cheering]
forget to daddy.
So because of the pressure that time,
one of my cousin that was in the house,
he said that he has to look for a way to
protect himself because the boy doesn't
really believe in God like that. So he
went to look for one small street cult
to join. He now went to join one like
and the boy is blind on the left eye. So
So he went to join them and they asked
him what he can do. He said he can be a
spy
with one eye.
So to cut the long story short now that
they all dead in the G because he is the
cause whenever the enemies are coming
from the left he doesn't see them. He
always sees with the right and he be
shouting the coast is clear the coast is
clear.
He just came and carried everybody like
that.
No yeah a lot a lot has happened. Ah so
much has happened that day. If you see I
don't know why people people are just
like this in this in this country
whenever they they they see you they
they always they always want to to
advise you
yes or I don't know they just feel they
just feel they just feel like I didn't
spend that money very well. So anytime
people see me they always want to advise
me and there is one thing because they
always call me on the phone there is one
thing they always talk they always have
one language those kind of people they
always tell you I be come out for where
you there I want to talk to you I don't
know I don't know what they see in that
thing that time that that money came
somebody just called me say ah aa where
you there I said I lo
so they don't give you your money I said
yes so hey thank god Oh, I become for
where you there I want to talk to you.
So I I I shifted I shifted from where I
was. He started advising me and advising
me. All of a sudden before I knew it
another person called that was my
auntie. She said ah my son where you I
say mommy I go so hey thank God though
you don't come much shame for your
family. I I say yes. So she said
so then don't give you your money. I
said yes. Yeah. Yeah.
I feel comfort. Where are you there? I
want talk to you.
[laughter]
>> Thank you very much.
[cheering]
>> Yeah.
Now they all right.
I try.
>> We just we be like the only surviving
people for Nigeria.
Plenty things don't happen for this
country this year.
Things were not supposed to happen this
year happened inside this year.
And out of everything we happen now now
two things now I notice. The first thing
why I realize say we think they kill us
for this country.
No be bandits or politics or anything.
No think they kill us for Nigeria.
Now opinion
our opinion for this country too plenty.
Now we think our opinion done to plenty
for this country. Now we think the
number one thing where they kill us with
that opinion. opinion too plenty
and why anywhere you see me now I know
they won't give my opinion again
I know they give I know they no matter
what happen you not see me they give
opinion anywhere
I don't get opinion I get forward they
use normally I get four opinion but you
don't ever see me they give opinion
anywhere again they keep my opinion if I
see go buy my opinion I go sell more
change this December I go give opinion
outside Again keep my opinion to myself
now. Opinion opinion too plenty. I just
pray if government put law say as a
Nigerian from next year make everybody
not get past two opinion again everybody
two two opinion per year if you use your
two opinion finish you go wait till next
year.
You go shorten the way people they talk
for the country because people they talk
too much. Go go go comment section you
go see 5,000 comments now because of
unlimited opinion now why people they
talk plenty like that if they reduce the
opinion you go see 12 comments could be
milestone people they happy for 12
comment this one with opinion too much
too plenty for the country
opinion finish you go they call your
friends they borrow opinion
I be James quick one here I be one
comment section like this I need
contribute something I don't know you
don't use your opinion finish if you
just send me one opinion I beg why
normally my opinion the day by this time
of year and that Mr. I use the wedding
finish my opinion [laughter]
if you just send me one opinion I don't
beg you opinion before why you behave
like this one opinion why they ask you
now July just ah it go make sense make
sense the second thing where I notice
way they worry us for this country or
the second thing where I notice we go
help us for this country they say I
don't realize say this country we don't
reach to get our own calendar 12 months
not of it carry us again for one year
[laughter]
and 12 months not going to reach us
again cuz the things happen for the
country plenty past the months where we
get and so we need about 16 months now
for Nigeria to complete one year and 12
months not going to reach us again cuz
the things happen to PL and it stress
God I know say God said they try best to
help us make sure say everything happen
inside one year because we know we
stress we stress God well they stress
too
It's too much because now why any time
where I see people they complain say how
this plenty things go happen inside only
November I follow them complain I say
now God they work and God they try help
us they try compress happen for 3 months
make it happen inside one month make
everywhere they balance yes because if
you don't do like that now we come they
get carry over to the next year and as a
nation you know good be better name say
we get carry over you know good like
that so they try compress things make
happen inside and The eye you know the
calculation. You know the calculation
where God go through to compress 3
months into one. You know the
calculation to go calculate every day
for
yeah we don't have enough space again
sorry for Muslim God
chai chai chai chai chai chai chai chai.
I show for kaduna on Sunday. to go use
Kai now you ch for your child
we don't have enough space in you what
do we do now what my problem is this guy
this Ned woko and his wives they're
taking all the spaces that's my issue
now okay see what we do put Ned woko and
bandit in one month [laughter]
add Donald Trump to one month let it let
it happen in one month now the angel go
ah that will be too much for when do you
know what will happen in December I'm
the one who sees tomorrow. I say add
everything. What is wrong with you?
[applause] I'm the one who sees the
future and you're telling me add this
thing. Uh-uh. We still have enough. We
still have a little space there, right?
Yeah, that's a little space we still
have there. Okay, let's see what we can
put. Uh, okay. Very dark man fighting
over Jalof. Sorry. Fighting with Jolof.
Put it Put it there. Put Puty Dark Man
there. Go add that one. Go look. Okay,
that that's enough. When you put all
these things, please shut the doors and
the windows cuz a lot of people in
Nigeria are going to cry to me in
December. I don't want to hear their
voice. Just shut everything. They cry. I
don't not ready for that rubbish. Let
them cry their blood out.
No, I don't see the next world war
happen for this country.
[applause]
The next world war we go for this for
this world. Now bloggers goat.
I don't see finish now bloggers now go
start the next world war. Yes. Because
then just something if if no say we know
if no say we see the video when very
dark man and jolov they fight bloggers
for don't spoil the whole thing happened
there something we take our IC bloggers
we just go write anything we concern
them which one we go write something
happen say
Mr. your love socks very man's breast
which kind which kind when that one
happen
when that kind of thing happen video all
of us take our IC
lie like that blog cause problem for
this country it's not right it's not
things the way it happen
when I see the news he shock me I say
Mr.
s very dark man
it didn't shock me I begin call because
I lie to the know the truth when I see
those things I call some people they
close to Mr. Jol see
guy shock person and they tell me say no
say Mr. do that kind say Mr. of lacto
intolerance treat
like that they lie like this for the guy
head they talk things not happen it's
not right now
[cheering]
>> I don't respond to treatment I
I know do plenty things so just they
bath three times a day
but t
don't small since last year
say I don't grow finish
no sweet me say grow say this our
generation one of our biggest
achievement be that we grow Week all of
us just rush grow grow everybody grow
grow grow grow grow grow grow grow grow
grow grow grow grow so they come grow
come jam adulthood way surprise
everybody
this adult would surprise people well
well ah surprise you know get some
adults where never believe say their
original life then they live so then
then they hope say one day then just
wake up from sleep as 5 years speaking
just realize all they suffer now dream
Now your real life be this go live
[clears throat]
go live the lifeh
remember when people they talk I can't
wait to be 30 I can't wait to be 30
it is not so 30 day don't see 30 now you
see and say you 30 but something
something inside you they tell you say
you and 30 not be met
you reach 30 so if If you if you beg if
you never become adult yet no go they
rush they mature
just 15 years don't get fully face they
do like that take your time grow small
this not be generation where they get
full face anyhow just like that take
your time step by step
cuz anything make them begin call you
auntie or brother your own don't finish
for this country I tell you the way
things go cost for you. You go believe
just overnight things just start to cost
and only you see other person they see
only those around 30 or above 30 they
know say things they cost just even me
they talk safe
no adulthood go be I don't even bother
myself grow rich like this
left to me I for just stop to grow
around that 2007 just when I see s near
adulthood Just stop stop to grow that
year just p for 2007 in 2007 land now
50,000
price well 35,000 you go get her I come
grow no no no no no adult I find all
means I try my best to make sure say I
avoid anything where concern adulthood I
try my best every day that my fight be
that anything just concern adult avoid
them they avoid Well, well even they
find now people tell me they behave like
small
one me if I wake up for morning first
question why one year why you behave
like small
and those ones they motivate me yes now
cuz I notic if you just once you cross
30 you get what they happen once you
cross 30 it be like say your head go
just open make problem begin to enter
Yes like somebody open door for your
head problem every day new problem enter
every day new problem enter
reach one time space go your head again
your head go come tight with problem
problem everywhere problem even your
brain no go see somewhere stay for the
head problem go push your brain push
your your brain come bend
like
your land from here to there that's four
plots
And so your brain got so if you day and
you don't cross 30 chances they very
high so your brain day right now
people above 30 then they they they
suffer you know say get the problem go
fool your head rich and they the problem
they come begin they argue with each
other.
Yeah. So inside your head all your
problem just be they argue which of them
where you go first think about.
Yeah. Family problem just come out one
morning say now me go think about today
as in they talk another problem go reply
and say who you be with think about you
two times in a row. No, because
yesterday think about you. Now you be
the only problem there. You know they
see other problem they are tobacos here
whenever complain you don't know why you
know they complain you just come you
think about
as in they argue just shout from corner
may nobody follow me drag on Saturday
now me think about on Saturday
as they talk that one light bill go this
one where they quarrel I sure say give
me space he say you not worry if I go
follow me go use my slot together you
light You mean we together? No worry.
Let's go. So now your problem just they
argue you know. No. So now with adults
they go through be that children them
they go through all those things. Now
children they enjoy pass only play play
play play play play play play play play
play play play play play. Children now.
Why you not ever see small picking where
they mad?
Every time only adults they mad every
matter where you go. I never ever see
small picking where they crazy before.
Every time adult adult you see even if
they send even if they send juuju for
you say make you mad the come when you
be small they wait when you don't turn
adult
now for their graduation day as say
congratulations wake up begin to wake
everything so Philip take m
so you know they come small once you
grow this
>> they wait mean you grow first
no and to be honest if we Look mad
people where well it goes say get things
where we as normal people supposed they
learn from them.
Yes, we know they study mad people
enough and I know say I not go believe
mad people they know they discriminate
on each other
then they look at each other equally
nobody big pass anybody for madness now
why they see say mad man we don't they
mad since 10 years ago with mad man we
just start to mad last month two of them
they chop for the same dust bean they
chop it see you go the other one they
say you just start to m disembark from
my din go chop for another bean
You just started mad last morning then
they do all those things then no see mad
man just they they behave no they don't
they get good relationship with each
other and I don't see two mad men where
they trek together before for Lagos yeah
they t together I don't they observe
them like 3 weeks sometimes they go face
vi
sometimes they go face a I come they
very curious I come they ask people I
say what happen with These two mad men
they track together every time. So now
people come they explain to me they say
actually one of them know they stay for
Lagos but two of them be friends. Say
but one they base for Los said that one
they stay for bani said that one day the
one with Bini come visit the one day
Lagos. So I come visit and go back the
one with Legos.
This one come visit me like this all the
way from Bi. I see go back. So make I
escort you.
Now take escort from Lagos to Pini.
So when come back
say ah so you escort me all the way from
Lagos come bene. So
all the adventure where we see for road
all the rotten banana where we chop for
make escort you go back to Lagos
now take escort go back Lagos. So when
anyone come back that one come they look
and say ah my guy
this your gesture where you show me so
where you escort me from pine come Lagos
which kind friend I go be if I don't
escort you go back to pini
so for 3 years now they don't escort
each other like that just all their leg
don't swell finish they don't g up they
still escort each other you they see the
bond between m people we normal people
Now you just escort your friend rich
gate don't they tell you put something
for fire you think those mad men don't
get something for fire for them they
escort interstate you see mad people
I know they talk from mind they talk
about mad men I don't want talk about
mad women
no worry mad women have no smile mad
women then smart then smart like normal
women too I don't see two mad women
where they fight because of one mad man
before
serious fight they fight break each
other because of the maybe save the man
too handsome
just say they stay for the biggest dos
been with the area
they see say even for madness women they
recognize success
[cheering]
how we hear of this
>> so I beg anything where they do even
just try succeed anything where you do
make sure you are successful even if
madness be successful cuz if you don't
succeed for real life, any other thing
where you go do, you go show say you not
be successful person. If you don't
succeed real life, you go mad. You go
show say you not be successful mad man.
Yes. Now because you go get your own
does been people does be you borrow it
go stay
you suffer well if you don't succeed.
Yes. True. Now
so
see you don't go scratch that. Don't
make me forget the next thing. What I
want
then say make I stop y too much. Good
man.
[cheering]